Register of the Korean subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Korean subject collection
1945-2010
XX759
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Pamphlets, bulletins, leaflets, and other printed matter relating to political, social, and economic conditions in North and South Korea, and to the Korean War.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Articles, booklets, brochures, bulletins, election material, flyers, leaflets, pamphlets, propaganda, reports, and speeches relating mainly to Korean political and social conditions and to the Korean War and its aftermath, arranged alphabetically by subject.
Korean War, 1950-1953.; Propaganda.; Korea--History.; Korea (North)--History.; Korea (South)--History.
- Foreign relations - United States, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Pamphlets issued by the Korea-America Friendship Society, in Korean.
- Korean War, 1950-1953
  - Armistice, 1955
    Article by Admiral C. Turner Joy entitled "Blunders Behind the Korean Truce: An Inside Story of How the U.S. Lost the Armistice."
  - Propaganda
    Leaflets issued by the Chinese Government during the Korean War and aimed at American troops.
- Korea (North), 1990
  Political tract by Kim Jong Il entitled "The Workers' Party of Korea Organizes and Guides all the Victories of Our People."
- Korea (South)
  - General, 1989-1991
    Booklets and brochures relating to Korean society and the Korean people.
  - Opposition, 1991
    Pamphlets and flyers issued by the International Committee for Peace and Reunification of Korea, Washington, D.C.
  - Propaganda and election material
    Includes bulletins and leaflets, circa 1948, issued by the South Korean Government, U.S. occupation authorities, and South Korean communists, for distribution in South Korea. In Korean and English.
  - Public opinion, 1945-1946
    Reports prepared by the United States Armed Forces in Korea relating to political trends in South Korea.
  - Roh Tae Woo, 1989-1991
    Speeches by and biographical material on President Roh.
- North-South relations
  - Booklet, 1991 March
    Published by the International Affairs Bureau of the Central Standing Committee of the General Association of Korean Residents in Japan (Chongryun) and relating to U.S. nuclear forces in South Korea aimed at North Korea.
  - Pamphlet
    Issued by the UN Korean War Allies Association and relating to the incident of 18 August 1976 at Panmunjom, South Korea, when North Korean soldiers attacked United Nations Command personnel.
  - Report, 1991 October
    Co-sponsored by the Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis and the Sejong Institute relating to the implications for regional stability and defense planning.
- Rest of collection not yet described (Box 2)